ocra.com 2004-12-23

# Privacy Policy & Use of this Website :: OCRA

PRIVACY POLICY   
Last Updated: 5th October 2004 

» Introduction  
» Application of this Privacy Policy  
» External Review of this Privacy Policy  
» Sites covered by this Privacy Policy  
» Links to Non-OCRA Worldwide Websites  
» Browsing OCRA Worldwide Websites  
» How we treat Personal Information  
» Keeping your Personal Information secure  
» Access to and accuracy of your Personal Information  
» Sharing or disclosing Personal Information  
» Distribution of Personal Information outside the EEA  
» Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
» Contacting Us

### Introduction

The Members of OCRA Worldwide respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. 

We have structured our websites so that, in general, you can visit OCRA Worldwide on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. 

### Application of this Privacy Policy

OCRA Worldwide provides this Privacy Policy to describe our privacy practices relating to persons who are not our clients and the choices such persons can make about the way personal information is collected and how that information is used. This Privacy Policy applies to: 

  * Visitors to our websites, who interact with our websites in any way (including by the completion of online forms, sending us email or subscription to our email newsletter).
  * Persons who communicate with OCRA Worldwide by any other method (such as by telephone, facsimile or letter)

This Privacy Policy ceases to apply when persons contract with us and become our clients as our terms relating to client privacy and confidentiality are contained in our Terms of Business. Clients should note that the privacy and confidentiality provisions in our Terms of Business differ from this Privacy Policy. 

### External Review of this Privacy Policy

By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine Privacy Programme we have made a commitment to meet the programme's strict requirements regarding how we treat any information you may submit to us through www.ocra.com and have had our privacy policy and related procedures verified by BBBOnLine. Further information about The BBBOnLine Privacy Programme is available at [www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/). 

Certain Members of OCRA Worldwide, such as OCRA (Mauritius) Limited, OCRA (Luxembourg) S.A. and Madeira Management Companhia Limitada, operate their own web sites and their privacy and security policies and websites have not being verified by BBBOnLine. 

Additionally and in order to enhance the protection of your privacy and our compliance with this Privacy Policy, OCRA (Isle of Man) Limited has become a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program and we have agreed to disclose our information practices and to have our practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organisation whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, OCRA Worldwide has agreed to notify you of: 

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by OCRA Worldwide. 
  * The organisation collecting the information. 
  * How the information is used. 
  * With whom the information may be shared. 
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under OCRA Worldwide's control. 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact OCRA Worldwide by emailing [privacy@ocra.com](mailto:privacy@ocra.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your enquiry or your enquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at [www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with OCRA Worldwide to resolve your concerns. 

### Sites Covered by this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to all Members of OCRA Worldwide and domains owned by Members of OCRA Worldwide (the "OCRA Worldwide Websites"). 

### Links to Non-OCRA Worldwide Websites

The OCRA Worldwide Websites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave our websites. OCRA Worldwide does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from OCRA Worldwide's. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. OCRA Worldwide's Privacy Policy does not cover the personal data you choose to give to unrelated third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information. 

### Browsing OCRA Worldwide Websites

If you visit any OCRA Worldwide Website and do not complete any online forms or communicate with us in any other way, you should note that: 

> Members of OCRA Worldwide will not collect or retain any personal data from web visitors who view pages on our websites and do not complete online forms or communicate with us in any other way. 
> 
> Our servers will seek to place a cookie on your computer so that we may track statistics relating to new and repeat visitors and other information which is not personally identifiable. A cookie is a piece of data placed on a user's hard drive containing information that enables unique web visitors to be identified for the purposes of analysing user interaction with a website. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information. We do not seek to associate cookies with the completion of online forms. We use cookies to track how visitors move through our sites and how often they visit. On most browsers, you can elect to decline to accept cookies. Should you decline to accept cookies your browsing experience will not be degraded. 
> 
> We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer our websites, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 
> 
> An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web, allowing Web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and utilise online forms and processes. 

### How we treat Personal Information

If you complete an online form or communicate with us by any means, Members of OCRA Worldwide will collect personal data from you, will communicate with you and use this personal data to facilitate supplying services and products. This may mean that personal data is passed to firms and organisations that are not Members of OCRA Worldwide for purposes relating to supplying our services such as shipping services and other third-party service providers acting upon our request to fulfil your requests. The personal data we collect includes information relating to contact information (such as name, address and telephone), identity information (such as passport number, nationality and place of birth) and such other information as may be required to facilitate supplying services and products. 

OCRA Worldwide may utilise personal data to provide reference notes, guidelines, advice and for marketing such other services and products and providing such other information as Members of OCRA Worldwide may from time to time make available. If you do not wish to receive this type of information, you should advise us by contacting [privacy@ocra.com](mailto:privacy@ocra.com)

Our email newsletter is available to users who subscribe to it and instructions relating to terminating its despatch are contained in every email newsletter that is sent out. 

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your name and email address, as well as your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit our website. We do not store this information. The information is for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

### Keeping your Personal Information Secure

OCRA Worldwide is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, OCRA Worldwide has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. 

### Access to and accuracy of your Personal Information

OCRA Worldwide strives to keep your personal data accurate. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to maintain client data accuracy. We will provide you with access to your information and the opportunity to change your information.   
The most effective way to obtain information or change any personal information we may collect is to contact [privacy@ocra.com](mailto:privacy@ocra.com). Prior to making changes to personal data or releasing information we will confirm that email requests to [privacy@ocra.com](mailto:privacy@ocra.com) are genuine by comparing the information contained in email requests against our records and seeking confirmation by email to the email address we hold on record or by seeking written instructions. 

### Sharing or disclosing Personal Information

The personal information and personal data we collect is used only for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and in this manner, it is never sold, lent or leased to third parties. 

Members of OCRA Worldwide reserve the right to treat these obligations of privacy as not applicable when obliged by law. 

### Distribution of Personal Information outside the EEA

As some Members of OCRA Worldwide are outside the EEA and as the provision of services and products by Members of OCRA Worldwide may necessitate the transfer of personal data and personal information outside the EEA, users and potential clients must accept that this may mean that personal data may be transferred to countries that do not provide adequate protection of data in accordance with Article 26 (1) of the EU Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data. 

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If there are updates to the terms of our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes and update the revision date on this website, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. 

Prior to changing our Privacy Policy to allow new unrelated uses of your personal data we will post a notice on our home page advising that our Privacy Policy will be changing in 30 days and send you an email so that you may choose not to accept these new unrelated uses of your personal data. 

### Contacting Us

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please send them to the [privacy@ocra.com](mailto:privacy@ocra.com). 

OCRA (Isle of Man) Limited  
Grosvenor Court  
Tower Street  
Ramsey, Isle of Man IM8 1JA  
British Isles
